REGINALD PRINCE

Atlanta, Ga Phone: *678.521.6313*

Email: Regprince788@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/princereginald0724/

GitHub: https://github.com/Reggieir44

Portfolio: https://reggiejr44.github.io/my-tech-portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with proven talent for aligning business strategy and objectives with established process development and operations management paradigms to achieve maximum impacts with minimum resource expenditures. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Growth-focused thought leader driven to establish effective optimization strategies and staff management to foster revenue growth. Exceptionally dedicated professional with keen interpersonal, communication, and organizational skills, as well as budget management, policy development, and resource allocation expertise.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technical Proficiencies: Windows, Mac OS, Microsoft Exchange, Microsoft Office Suite, Google Suite

Computer Science Applied to JavaScript: Algorithms (Searches, Sorts), Performance, Time Complexity, Big O Notation, Data Structures, Design Patterns

Browser-Based Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, Progressive Web Applications, Local Storage, Session Storage, Indexed DB, React.js

API Design: Client-Server Model, REST API, JSON, AJAX (Fetch API), HTTP request methods, GraphQL

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB (Mongoose)

Server-Side Development: Node.js, Express.js, User Authentication, Template Engines, MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js)

Additional Technologies: Python, Java, Amazon Web Services, C#

Deployment and Delivery: Heroku, Git, GitHub Pages, Shell Scripting, Unit Testing, Linting, Continuous Integration

PROJECTS

Progressive Web Applications (PWA): Text Editor
Link to GitHub Repo: https://github.com/Reggiejr44/pwa-my-j-a-t-e
Link to Deployed Project: https://pwa-my-j-a-t-e.herokuapp.com/

• **Project Description:** A text editor that meets the PWA criteria and features a number of data persistence techniques that serve as redundancy in case of the options is not supported by the browser. The application will also function offline.

- **Core Responsibilities:** I'm the sole contributor. Responsible for the entire Full-Stack project.
- Languages Used: <u>Node.js.</u> Express.js, Heroku, Babel, Javascript, IndexedDB, Webpack & WebpackPwaManifest Plugins

Model-View-Controller (MVC): Tech Blog

Link to GitHub Repo: https://github.com/Reggiejr44/model-view-controller-mytechblog Link to Deployed Project: https://modelviewcontroller-mytechblog.

- Project Description: This is a full-stack CMS-style blog site where users can publish
 posts and comment on other users' blog posts. With login authentication, logged-in users
 have access to the dashboard where they can also edit or delete their posts and or
 comments. Additionally, this application is MVC structured and makes use of multiple
 packages such as handlebars, bcrypt, express.sessions, sequelize and more to ensure
 the most optimized experience.
- **Core Responsibilities:** I'm the sole contributor. Responsible for the entire Full-Stack project.
- Languages Used: Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars Template Engine, Bcrypt, Sequelize, Dotenv, Heroku, Javascript

Interactive Front-End Application: The match made in heaven

Link to GitHub Repo: https://github.com/oliviasylee/match-made-in-heaven/ Link to Deployed Project: https://oliviasylee.github.io/match-made-in-heaven/

- **Project Description:** My first interactive Front-End Application. Many people find it difficult to look for recipes they need to make a certain dish and sometimes it's hard to choose what drink they want to match it with. Our team has created a web application that helps people decide what food and drink to enjoy together. With just one click, users can select from a variety of cuisine types, and we will provide them with a selection of ingredients and recipes, along with a random drink recipe to match.
- **Core Responsibilities:** I'm the sole contributor. Responsible for the entire Full-Stack project.
- Languages Used: HTML, CSS Framework: Materialize CSS, jQuery, Fetch API, APIs: The Edamam API, The Cocktail DB

EXPERIENCE

EQUITYLIFESTYLE, SAN DIEGO, CA, SEPTEMBER 2021 TO PRESENT

ASSISTANT PROPERTY MANAGER

- Filled out lease forms or agreements and accumulated rental deposits from 200+ tenants
- Kept work areas in a clean and orderly manner with a strong awareness of property curb appeal
- Learned all lease terms, specifications and community policies, telephone and sales techniques, and current market conditions
- Communicated consistently with all apartment locator services and local businesses to offer updated information and resources
- Performed an on-going resident retention program under the direction of the Property Manager
- Led the proper maintenance of all resident and property files and updated the Advertising Log Book

- Handled all required administrative forms, reports and related information
- Tracked unusual or extraordinary circumstances regarding the property or residents.
- Supported the Manager in the collection of delinquent rents and organized resident activities such as community get togethers, food drives, kids night, community clean-up, beach clean-ups, raffle contest, resident of the month and a weekly community breakfast
- Oversaw vendor contacts and scheduling of community projects, financial invoices, and community compliance
- Connected with residents and designed signs around the property

INTERSOLUTIONS, SAN DIEGO, CA, JUNE 2021 TO SEPTEMBER 2021

LEASING CONSULTANT

- Manages lease form competition and agreements, coalescing and collecting rental deposits
- Directed model units and ensured preparation for showings, maintaining clean and work areas, and fostered curb appeal
- Preserved strong knowledge of lease terms, specifications, community policies, telephone and sales techniques, current market conditions, rental rates, sizes, locations and all amenities of property
- Continued and revised necessary contacts with all apartment locator services and local businesses to offer effective informational material
- Progressed an on-going resident retention program under the direction of the Property Manager
- Acted as primary contact for issues regarding the renewal process, property maintenance of all resident and property files, and log book revisions
- Processed all required administrative forms, reports and related information
- Reported any unusual or extraordinary circumstances regarding the property or residents
- Assisted the Assistant Manager with the collection of delinquent rents and the planning of resident activities such as community engagement events (pool parties, meet and greets), community athletic competitions and tournaments (dodgeball, basketball, kickball)

ASPIRE, SAN DIEGO, CA, JANUARY 2020 TO JULY 2021

JUNIOR DIRECTOR SALESMAN

- Prepared morning and nightly meetings to establish the daily tasks and needs
- Ensured consistent staffing through recruiting, selecting, orienting, and training efforts
- Attained successful staff results through clear communication of job expectations, including outlined planning, monitoring, and appraising of job results
- Marketed and sold products and services using strong, evidence-based arguments with existing and prospective customers
- Implemented cost-benefit and needs analyses of existing and potential customers to exceed expectations
- Cultivated and continued positive business and customer relationships to facilitate constant revenue growth
- Accelerated the resolution of customer concerns and complaints to maximize satisfaction
- Accomplished the agreed upon sales targets and outcomes within schedule constraints
- Managed sales efforts with team members and other departments and reviewed the territory and market's potential, track sales and status reports

COCA-COLA, ATLANTA, GA, JUNE 2015 TO AUGUST 2019

- Executed the gathering and preparation of marketing, foundation development, and finance files within strict deadlines and in alignment with specific needs and requests
- Originated strategies for maximum production and organization within the marketing and sales departments
- Formulated reports, correspondence and spreadsheets with Microsoft Office programs regarding finances, alumni collections and records
- Liaised with staff and customers by phone and email regarding missing or needed information and compiled retrieved information into files
- Recorded incoming and outgoing files and materials and retained accurate records for potential discrepancy tracking
- Collected physical files and digitized records organized for simplified revisions and retrieval by authorized team members

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp Certificate: Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

Highschool Diploma: Riverwood International Charter School, Atlanta, GA